if you have anxiety all night long you
probably have anxiety during the day you
probably have a very stressful life you
really should assess the stressors go
ahead and grab a piece of paper and
write down the top three things in your
life that if I handed you a magic wand
right now and I said you can eliminate
these aspects what would they be and
write those down and then work on
deriving a plan working backwards what
is the first thing that needs to happen
or the last thing needs to happen before
this item is gone and build a plan down
to where you are today and follow that
blueprint to get rid of that stressor
once you eliminate the top stressors in
your life your anxiety should reduce and
then you should be able to have better
sleep you're going to bed with a lot of
worries on your mind and it is keeping
you up okay so guess what it's a
snowball effect the worse you sleep the
worse your next day is going to be the
more anxious you're going to be and the
most more irritable you're going to be
that leads to emotional decisions which
always lead to mistakes and mistakes
lead to more stress so this snowballing
effect needs to be nipped by stopping
identifying and correcting it's very
similar to the medical model we do an
assessment by getting the subjective
data from the patient by looking at the
objective aspects that are presented to
us putting them together and deriving a
blueprint on how we fix the problem by
diagnosing the problem if you don't
diagnose the root cause of your stresses
you will never be able able to truly
eliminate or fix them and you have to
understand I can't stress it enough the
longer it lingers the worse it gets
because you're going to continue to make
mistakes and lead a life of irritability
it's only going to get worse this is
evidenced by guys in their 40s and 50s
they look extremely rundown overweight
um you know just completely falling
apart they look 10 15 years older than
they are and that is because they have
gone through chronic stress that has
never been
addressed and you know they're up at 3:
in the morning they're up at three you
look at their social media post they're
always 2 three in the morning right yeah
have to stress get rid of alcohol and if
you live on caffeine listen I love
coffee I have one in the morning that's
it for the day I know guys drink five
six cups of coffee a day you'll never
sleep you will never sleep get rid of
stimulants all right get rid of
amphetamines like adero get rid of
caffeine get rid of Al get rid of the
things that are causing you to be up at
night